Guide to the Silas Reed Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Reed, Henrietta M. Rogers (Mrs. Silas). 25 letters to her husband. [Summer, 1859]-September 3, 1886. 86 pp., 2 postcards.
---- 12 letters to her daughter, Clara Anthony. July 28, 1859- August 21, 1875. 49 pp.
Richards, John F. Letter to Reed. January 4, 1884. 1 p.
Richardson, W. Letter to Reed. December 16, 1873, enclosing "Resolution of Council" November 24, 1873, to send to Reed in Washington a copy of Joint Resolution No. 7, signed by F. E. Warren. 2 pp. With a printed copy of the Joint Resolution, signed: "A true copy of the original memorial as passed by the two Houses of the 3d Legislative Assembly, Wyoming Ter., W. Richardson, Secretary." 3 pp.
Robison, Belle Reed (Mrs. Joseph). Letter to her father, Silas Reed. November 24, [1857?]. 2 pp.
---- 13 letters to her mother. March 21, 1854-January 29, 1863. 48 pp.
Rogers, Alfred M. Letter to his uncle, Dr. Reed. June 7, 1878. 6 pp.
Rogers, Henry M. Four letters to Clara Anthony. June 22, 1872- July 3, 1882. 10 pp.
---- Letter to Nathan Anthony. July 27, 1871, with note on verso from Anthony to Reed. 1 p.
---- Letter to Henry G. Hay. [July 3, 1882.] Copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to Mr. Hayward. [July 3, 1882.] Copy. 1 p.
---- 25 letters to his uncle, Silas Reed. June 13, 1871- June 28, 1886. 87 pp.
---- Two letters to Mrs. Reed. March 12, October 30, 1872. 6 pp.
---- Letter to Alex. White of White and Plowman. January 13, 1882. Letter press copy. 2 pp.
Rogers, John Hicks. Letter to his brother-in-law, Silas Reed. May 12, 1885. 2 pp.
Russell, J. Letter to Reed. December 25, 1841. 3 pp.
Scott, Thomas A. Letter to Reed. March 3, 1875. 1 p.
Seay and Kiskaddon. Letter to Reed. July 19, 1873. 1 p.
Seay and Woodside. Agreement to try the case of Reed vs. Greenman, Salem, Mo., April 12, 1875. 2 pp.
Sheldon and Waterman. Letter to H. M. Rogers. June 12, 1872. Copy. 4 pp.
Shy, A. H. Letter to Reed. January 12, 1876. 1 p.
Simmons, R. P. Letter to O. K. Smith. November 18, 1841. 1 p.
Simmons, S. Letter to Reed. November 21, 1872. Copy. 2 pp.
Simpson, James B. Letter to Colonel M. Henderson. August 5, 1881, enclosing a notice from the U.S. Circuit Court, Dallas, Texas, August 4, 1881, in the judgment Reed vs. Ira Harris to Jos. G. Graves or J. B. Simpson, his solicitor, signed by A. J. Houston. 4 pp.
Smith, Amos. Letter to Reed. September 2, 1875. 2 pp.
Smith, Charles H. Letter to Reed. November 10, 1841. 1 p.
Smith, Oliver H. Two letters to Reed. December 6, 9, 1841.
Signatures only. 3 pp.
---- Letter to Reed. February 9, 1842, with notes added by S. Prentiss, J. O. Balis, and N. P. Tallmadge. 2 pp.
---- Copy of the letter of February 9, 1842, with added note by R. J. Walker. 3 pp.
Snake Creek Mining District, Bylaws in operation to November 1885, signed by S. H. Epperson, chairman, R. B. Ross, secretary. Certified a true copy by N. C. Springer, recorder, C. H. Miller, deputy. October 22, 1881. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Map, in pencil, of part of Parley's Park mines, showing mines in Snake Creek District. 38 x 50 cm.
Souper, Thomas E. Letter to Reed. August 29, 1863. 1 p.
Steele, William R. Letter to Reed. April 22, 1873. 3 pp.
Steffens, Josephine (Mrs. D. J.). Letter to Reed. August 25, 1881. 1 p.
Stevens, Leverett C. Five letters to Reed. January 15, 1873- June 1, 1874. 12 pp.
Thirlwell, Charles H. Letter to Reed. January 31, 1882. 2 pp.
---- Agreement, May 22, 1882, signed by Reed and Thirlwell. 2 pp.
Thomas, John B. Six letters to Reed. November 14, 1869- June 17, 1886. 15 pp.
Tighe, John. Letter to Reed. October 23, 1872. Copy. 1 p.
Tutt, Henry. Letter to Senator Rives. June 23, 1841. 2 pp.
Tweed, W. N. Memorandum of agreement, Tweed mines. December 19, 1882, signed by Reed and Tweed. 3 pp.
Tyler, John. Letter to Reed. March 31, 1873. 3 pp.
Tyler, Lyon G. Three letters to Reed. March 31, 1885-May 20, 1886. 10 pp.
U.S. Circuit Court, Eastern District of Missouri. Notice to take depositions in Boston in the case of George Hearst against James Halligan and others. Signed January 2, 1874, by Seay & Kiskaddon and Knox, attorneys for plaintiff. T. von B. Crews, attorney for defendants. Printed form. 1 p.
U.S. President, 1841-45 (John Tyler). Note signed J. T. on Reed's letter to the President. February 22, 1842.
U.S. President, 1869-77 (U. S. Grant). Letter to Reed. August 7, 1875. Copy. 2 pp.
U.S. Senate. Select Committee to whom were referred the memorials of Silas Reed. Report. In Senate of the United States, January 25, 1842. Ordered to be Printed in Confidence, for the Use of the Senate (27th Congress, 2d Session, Confidential, Executive No. 1). 5 pp.
---- Extract of so much of the Executive proceedings of the Senate as relates to the nomination of Silas Reed. In Senate of the United States, June 17, 1842. 3 pp.
U.S. Senate. Committee on Public Lands. Draft of a letter [to the President] framed by Colonel Birch for the signatures of the Committee, February 1842. Copy on the sheet with Caleb Cushing's letter of December 17, 1841. 1 p.
Urban, D. Order No. 4, to A. A. Surgeon Silas Reed. June 29, 1863. Signature only. 1 p.
Ward, George L. Two letters to Reed. December 6, 1841. March 30, 1842. The letter of March 30 a copy. 5 pp.
Warren, Winslow. Letter to Reed. June 18 [n.y.] 1 p.
Wash, Robert. Letter to Reed. October 31, 1841. 2 pp. With draft of a letter about Wash written by Reed. 2 pp.
Washburne, Elihu B. Letter to Reed. November 15, 1879. 1 p.
Watson, Thomas. Letter to Thomas H. Benton. November 17, 1841. Copy. 1 p.
Wetmore, George P. Letter to Reed. August 12, 1869. 2 pp.
Wetmore, Henry. Three letters to Mrs. Reed. August 23, 1869- October 13, 1886. 10 pp.
Wheeler, William S. Letter to Reed. January 7, 1861. 1 p.
White, Alexander. Three letters to Reed. October 16, 1879- May 18, 1882. Two are copies. 8 pp.
White, Rodgers. Letter to H. M. Rogers. December 23, 1881. 1 p.
White and Plowman. Two letters to H. M. Rogers. December 5 [i.e., January 5], January 23, 1882. 4 pp.
Whittlesey, Elisha. Letter to Thomas Ewing. March 24, 1841. Copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to Edwin M. Stanton. August 28, 1862. Copy. 2 pp.
Wilson, Joseph S. Notification to Reed of his appointment as surveyor general of Wyoming. March 5, 1870, signed by J. S. Wilson. Printed form. 1 p.
---- Letter to Reed. January 11, 1871. 1 p.
Wood, R. C. Letter to Reed. November 19, 1863. Copy. 1 p.
Wood, William. Letter to Reed. January 24, 1837. 1 p.
Wyoming Territory. Council. A bill to increase the number of members of the Territorial Council and House. Printed, and certified a true copy by Jason B. Brown, Secretary, January 2, 1874. 1 p.
Zane, Orloff A. Letter to Reed. May 19, 1875. Copy. 1 p.
Appendix B: A list of miscellaneous documents of Silas Reed
Reed, Silas. Cipher, for use with Ward. [n.d.] 1 p.
---- Reed vs. Greenman. Notes on the case over the Densmore property. [April 1875.] 6 pp.
---- "Minutes of Salem, Mo., Suit, &c." Memoranda on the Densmore property and forged deeds. [1875?] 3 pp.
---- "Memorial to Congress." Draft of a letter in defense of Secretary Delano. [1876?] 9 pp.
---- Trial testimony, 1876. Dr. Reed's statement of the Jno. Delano contract. 16 pp.
---- Copy in pencil by Reed of L. C. Stevens' testimony. Pages 96-150 and 2 unnumbered [i.e., 57 pp.].
U.S. Congress. Committee on Expenditures in the Interior Department. Surveys in the Territory of Wyoming (44th Congress, 1st Session, House Report No. 792, August 2, 1878). Proof sheets. 7 pp.
Reed, Silas. Will, February 5, 1866, witnessed by Henry Wetmore and George P. Wetmore. 3 pp.
"Map of mining claims in Parley's Park, Utah. Compiled from Government & location surveys, by Jos. Gorlinski, C. A. and U. S. Mineral Surveys, 1882." New York, Lehmaier & Brother. 118 x 76 cm.
"Map of the property of the Uinta Mining Company, Ontario Mining Company ... Parley's Park, Utah Territory." New York, Lehmaier & Brother. Endorsed by Reed: "Dec. 18, 83." 32 x 23 1/2 cm.
"Free Missouri State Board of Immigration." St. Louis, L. Gast Bro. & Co. Lith. [n.d.] With estimates of lands and values by Reed on the same sheet. 26 1/2 x 20 cm.
"Yellowstone National Park, from surveys made under the direction of F. V. Hayden ... 1871." Compiled and drawn by E. Hergesheimer, J. Bien, photolith. [n.p., n.d.] 28 x 30 cm.
Reed, Silas. Cash accounts March 18, 1870-January 16, 1871. 28 pp. 14 1/2 cm. Original binding.
---- "Copies of telegrams & correspondence between Dr. Silas Reed and Henry M. Rogers about the Reward Mine." November 13- December 25, 1882. Copied by Clara Anthony. 41 pp. 21 cm. Original binding.
---- "Lands of M.S. and M.L. Co. in Jefferson, Co., Mo." 7 pp. 14 1/2 cm. Original binding.
---- Park City, Utah, mine book. "Cash received for mining purposes in Utah." May 3, 1874-August 1875. 30 pp. 16 1/2 cm. Original binding.
Appendix C: Name and Subject Added Entries
Anthony, Arthur Cox, 1866-
Anthony, Clara James Reed, 1840-
Anthony, Nathan, 1832-1881
Anthony, Nathan, Jr., 1872-
Anthony, Silas Reed, 1863-
Delano, Columbus, 1809-1896
Drummond, Willis
Hay, Henry G.
Hearst, Phoebe Anderson, 1842-1919
Henderson, Malcolm
Macomber, Clara Elizabeth Robinson, 1858-
Reed, Henrietta Maria Rogers
Reed, Silas, 1807-1886
Robinson, Belle Reed, d. 1863
Rogers, Henry Munroe, 1839-1937
Thomas, John B., fl. 1869-1886
Missouri Smelting and Mineral Lands Company
United States. President (1841-1845: Tyler)
United States. President (1869-1877: Grant)
Dallas and Wichita Railroad.
Mines and mineral resources--Missouri
Mines and mineral resources--Utah
Missouri--History
Snake Creek Mining District
Wyoming--History
Mines and mineral resources -- Missouri; Mines and mineral resources -- Utah; Missouri -- History; Snake Creek Mining District; Wyoming -- History; Maps -- Utah; Surgeons -- Missouri; Surgeons -- Tennessee; Surveyors -- Illinois; Surveyors -- Missouri; Surveyors -- Wyoming; Anthony, Arthur Cox, 1866-; Anthony, Clara James Reed, 1840-; Anthony, Nathan, Jr., 1872-; Anthony, Nathan, 1832-1881; Anthony, Silas Reed, 1863-; Delano, Columbus, 1809-1896; Drummond, Willis; Hay, Henry G.; Hearst, Phoebe Apperson, 1842-1919; Henderson, Malcolm; Macomber, Clara Elizabeth Robinson, 1858-; Reed, Henrietta Maria Rogers; Reed, Silas, 1807-1886; Robinson, Belle Reed, -1863; Rogers, Henry Munroe, 1839-1937; Thomas, John B., active 1869-1886; United States. President (1841-1845: Tyler); United States. President (1869-1877: Grant); Dallas and Wichita Railroad; Missouri Smelting and Mineral Lands Company
- Diaries, 1872-81; Series I; 0.5; (1.25 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Diaries, consists of twelve volumes, around 1,895 pages in all, which cover the dates January 1, 1872, to August 29, 1874, and January 1, 1877, to January 31, 1881. The diaries record Dr. Reed's trips to and from Boston and Washington and throughout the West, letters and telegrams received and sent, and brief references to business and family affairs.
  - 1872 Jan 1-1873 Jan 9 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1873 Jan 1-Nov 23 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1873 Nov 23-1874 Aug 29 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1877 Jan 1-Apr 15 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1877 Apr 4-Dec 31 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1878 Jan 1-Apr 4 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1878 Apr 5-Jul 6 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1878 Jul 7-Oct 31 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1878 Nov-Dec (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1879 Dec 28-1880 Feb 9 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1880 Jan 11-Dec 31 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1881 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous Business Papers, 1870-82; Series II; 0.25; (.5 box)
  Series II, Miscellaneous Business Papers, consists of four manuscript volumes in which were kept cash and expense accounts, a record of correspondence and telegrams, and land records.
  - Cash account, 1870-71 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Record of correspondence and telegrams between Reed and Henry M. Rogers, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Mines and lands book of the Missouri Smelting and Mineral Lands Co. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Mine account book, 1874-75 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 1833-93; Series III; 2.7; (6.25 boxes)
  Series III, Correspondence, consists of letters written by Silas Reed to members of his family, including his wife Henrietta Maria Rogers. The letters written by Reed to others are usually drafts or copies. The family correspondence includes letters to members of the Reed and Anthony families from friends and relatives in the East and letters of the Anthony family written between 1890 and 1893, after the death of Dr. Reed.
  - Correspondence, 1833-38 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1841 Jan-Sept (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1841 Oct (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1841 Nov-Dec (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Memorials to the Senate, 1841-42 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1842-45 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1852-53, 1859 (Box 3, Folder 22a)
  - Correspondence, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Belle Reed Robinson letters, 1854-63 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1861-62 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1863 Mar-Aug (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1863-65 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1866-67 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1868 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1869-70 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, 1871 Jan-Jun (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1871 Jun-Dec (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1872 Jan-Apr (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1872 May-Jun (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, 1872 Jul-Aug (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence, 1872 Sep-Oct (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence, 1872 Nov-Dec (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence and papers, 1873 Jan-Mar (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence and papers, 1873 Apr-Jun (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence and papers, 1873 Jun-Aug (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence and papers, 1873 Sep-Dec (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence and papers, 1874 Jan-May (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence and papers, 1874 Jun-Dec (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence, 1875 Jan-Jul (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence, 1875 Aug-Dec (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence, 1876 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Testimony at Congressional Investigation, 1876 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence, 1877 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence and papers, 1878 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence and papers, 1879 Jan-Aug (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence and papers, 1879 Sep-Dec (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence, 1880 Jan-Mar (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence, 1880 Apr-Jul (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence, 1880 Aug-Dec (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence and papers, 1881 Jan-May (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence, 1881 May-Aug (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence, 1881 Sep-Dec (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Correspondence and papers, 1882 Jan-May (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence, 1882 Jun-Aug (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Correspondence, 1882 Sep-Nov 19 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence, 1882 Nov 22-Dec (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence, 1883 Jan-Jul (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Correspondence, 1883 Aug-Sep (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Correspondence, 1883 Oct (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Correspondence, 1883 Nov-Dec (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Correspondence, 1884 Jan-Mar (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence, 1884 Apr-Jul (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Correspondence, 1884 Aug-Sep (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Correspondence, 1884 Oct (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Correspondence, 1884 Nov-Dec (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Correspondence, 1885 Jan-May 19 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Correspondence, 1885 May 21-Jun (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Correspondence, 1885 Jul-Aug (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Correspondence, 1885 Sep-Oct (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Correspondence, 1885 Nov-Dec (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Correspondence, 1886 Jan-Mar (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - Correspondence, 1886 May (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Correspondence, 1886 Jun (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - Correspondence, 1886 Jul (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Correspondence, 1886 Aug-Sep (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Correspondence, 1886 Oct-Dec (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Undated correspondence (Box 8, Folder 82-3)
  - Family correspondence, 1890-93 (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Miscellaneous notes and papers (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Miscellaneous mementoes and photos (Box 8, Folder 86)
- Miscellaneous Legal Papers, 1845-90, n.d.; Series IV; 5; (1 box)
  Series IV, Miscellaneous Legal Papers, consists of miscellaneous business papers, deeds (some forged), declarations, affidavits, mining papers, maps, a few miscellaneous newspaper clippings, and papers and records dealing with the Olive Street house in St. Louis, Missouri. The last folder in the series consists of a typewritten itemized listing of the Reed papers and several markers with annotations, written in Mrs. Reed's hand.
  - Business papers (I), 1845-74 (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - Business papers (II), 1874-90?, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - Deeds, declarations, affidavits, 1858-77, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 89)
  - Deeds (forged), 1869-75, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - Olive St. house (St. Louis): deeds, etc., 1848-72, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 91)
  - Mining papers (I), 1869-77, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - Mining papers (II), 1874 (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Maps, 1871-82, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Newspapers clippings, 1881-83, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - Listing of collection and Mrs. Reed's markers (Box 9, Folder 96)
- Scrapbook, 1837-86; Series V; 5; (1 box)
  The scrapbook contains newspaper clippings from the years 1837 to 1886, although most of the clippings date from the years 1841 to 1844.
  - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings, 1837-86 (Box 10)